[
    {
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "What is HR1?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "AN ACT\nTo expand Americans’ access to the ballot box, reduce the\ninfluence of big money in politics, and strengthen ethics\nrules for public servants, and for other purposes. "
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Would tax payers money be sent to a political candidates campaign under the HR1 act?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "The money would actually come from a new \"Freedom From Influence Fund\" under the U.S. Treasury, which would collect funds from a 2.75 percent fee assessed on criminal and civil fines and penalties or settlements with banks and corporations that commit corporate malfeasance."
                    }
                ]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "What date does the claim refer to?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "2019."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "were any European counties giving financial support to Ukraine around 2019 and prior?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "The EU responded to the Ukraine crisis of 2014 with the 2014-2020 package of 11.2 billion euros"
                    }
                ]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "Did Nigeria paid off their entire foreign debt between 1999 and 2007 ?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "The data shows the Obasanjo government did not settle Nigeria’s foreign debt as the VP claimed. They handed over to a new government in May 2007. That year, Nigeria still spent more than $1 billion to service foreign debts."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "How much was Nigeria's foreign debt as at 2007?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "By 2006, our quantum of debt had come down to about $3.6 billion from almost $36 billion, only about 10 percent of what it was before we got $20 billion relief and we paid a little over $12 billion to the Paris Club (with a little out of it to the London Club to adjust our debt).”"
                    }
                ]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "Can the coronavirus be eliminated through drinking lots of water and gargling with warm water with salt/vinegar in it?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "As of now, WHO and experts have issued some basic protective measures against the novel coronavirus. These are:\n\n1) Wash your hands frequently\n2) Maintain social distancing\n3) Avoid touching eyes, nose and mouth\n4) Practice respiratory hygiene\n5) Seek early medical care if you have fever, cough and difficulty breathing\n6) Stay informed and follow advice given by your healthcare provider\n\nThe Press Information Bureau (PIB) has also debunked this rumour that coronavirus can be treated by gargling with warm water mixed with salt and vinegar.\n\n#Coronavirus CANNOT be treated by gargling with warm water mixed with salt and vinegar.\n\nThis is #fakenews circulating on social media and WhatsApp."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Can saline help prevent coronovirus at all?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "No",
                        "bool_explanation": "There is no evidence that saline has any effect on covid, and the WHO debunked a similar claim about nose rinsing with saline. "
                    }
                ]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "Who is Adam Schiff?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Democratic California Rep. Adam Schiff, the chairman of the House Intelligence Committee"
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Is there any evidence that Schiff ever settled a sexual harassment lawsuit with another man?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "No",
                        "bool_explanation": "There was no House Ethics Committee reports about sexual misconduct from the California congressman and no reports in news outlets either. "
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Does congress allow lawmakers to use taxpayer dollars for sexual harassment payouts?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "No",
                        "bool_explanation": "Congress passed a law in 2018 that makes lawmakers personally financially liable for sexual harassment payments and prohibits them from using taxpayer dollars in such settlements."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Where did this story likely originate from?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Likely from a satirical article posted on TheNetSpies, a website that disclaims it publishes content with “a bit of satire for laughs.” The article, posted in February 2018, claims Schiff abused a supposed “gay lover,” crediting an editor at the Los Angeles Times with providing the site with the exclusive story."
                    }
                ]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "What is the average monthly income in Saudi Arabia?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "$3737 per month in 2017-18"
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "What is the average monthly income in Nigeria?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Around $66.00 "
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "When was the claim made?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "01/10/2020"
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "What were the petrol prices for 2020 in Nigeria?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "the price of Premium Motor Spirit to N162 per litre"
                    },
                    {
                        "answer": "N151 per litre"
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "What were the petrol prices for 2020 in Saudi Arabia?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "From August 2020:\n\nGasoline 91: SAR 1.43 per liter\n\nGasoline  95: SAR 1.60 per liter "
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "What is the yearly average income in Nigeria?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "2,100 $\t"
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "What is the yearly average income in Saudi Arabia?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "22,270 $\t"
                    }
                ]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "Was there news coverage of President Trump signing an EO yesterday protecting pre-existing conditions?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Yes",
                        "bool_explanation": "The LA Times covered President Trump's travel to North Carolina on Thursday to announce his commitment to protecting Americans with pre-existing medical conditions and to issue another round of executive orders related to healthcare."
                    },
                    {
                        "answer": "Yes",
                        "bool_explanation_second": "Healthline covered President Trump's signing of the executive order that claims to help protect Americans with preexisting conditions like cancer, asthma, or diabetes."
                    },
                    {
                        "answer": "Yes",
                        "bool_explanation_third": "NBC News covered President Donald Trump's announcement of two new health care executive orders Thursday on protecting pre-existing conditions and preventing surprise billing as the president sought to shore up his support on an issue that remains top of mind to voters amid the ongoing coronavirus pandemic."
                    }
                ]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "Why did Democratic California Sen. Dianne say all vets are mentally ill in some way and government should prevent them from owning firearms?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "There is no evidence Feinstein ever made the comment. A Feinstein spokesperson denied the senator ever said it."
                    },
                    {
                        "answer": "There is no evidence Feinstein ever made the comment. A Feinstein spokesperson denied the senator ever said it and it appears nowhere on her social media "
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Were Quote from Dianne Feinstein about veterans and guns fabricated ?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "The quote appears to be a distortion of comments Feinstein made when she and other Democratic legislators introduced the Assault Weapons Ban of 2013 following the mass shooting in Newtown, Connecticut. While in a committee markup of the bill, Republican Texas Sen. John Cornyn proposed an amendment that would allow military veterans to be exempt from the ban, according to The Associated Press."
                    }
                ]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "What has the data on average deductions above $10,000 in New York counties shown?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "According to the most recent IRS data from the 2016 tax year, 53 counties had average deductions that were greater than $10,000."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "How is the average calculated?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "No answer could be found."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "How many New Yorkers took state and local tax deductions in 2016?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "No answer could be found."
                    },
                    {
                        "answer": "Residents of New York take the highest average deduction for state and local taxes, according to IRS data. In 2014, 34.14% of New York tax returns included a deduction for state and local taxes. The average size of those New York SALT deductions was $21,038.02. Residents of New York City will pay particularly high tax rates due to the local income taxes assessed there."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "How is so SALT calculations work?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Taxpayers who itemize their deductions (meaning they don’t take the standard deduction) can deduct what they’ve paid in certain state and local taxes. This SALT deduction includes property, income and sales taxes. More specifically, anyone who itemizes can deduct property taxes, but must choose between deducting their income taxes and sales taxes. Most choose to deduct their income taxes because those payments generally exceed sales tax payments. Residents of states with high income taxes (California, New York, New Jersey and Maryland, to name a few) generally opt to deduct their state and local income taxes if they itemize. Residents of states with high sales taxes (Louisiana, Texas and others) and low or nonexistent income taxes generally opt to deduct their sales taxes if they itemize. However, property taxes and income taxes — not sales taxes — are the primary drivers of the SALT deduction."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Is the way this average is calculated, an accurate portrayal of the data?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "No",
                        "bool_explanation": "Not every American takes the state and local tax deduction. High-income filers are much more likely to itemize and therefore more likely to take the SALT deduction. The higher your income, the more valuable tax deductions are to you in general because you’re taxed at a higher rate.\n\nWith the deduction for state and local taxes, the federal government is effectively subsidizing high earners in high-productivity states and cities. (Any deduction the federal government offers is a subsidy.) As you might expect, wealthy residents of wealthy states are most likely to pay state and local taxes. They also tend to have the highest average SALT deductions. According to the Tax Foundation, people with incomes over $100,000 receive more than 88% of SALT deduction benefits.\n\nThose who stand to gain from deducting their property taxes tend to be those who have expensive homes in prospering communities. Filers who deduct their state and local income taxes tend to be high earners in thriving states. States and cities with high income taxes also tend to be high-opportunity states like California and New York.\n\nThe latest data available, from 2016, before the new tax law was implemented, show that in 53 counties, the average state and local tax deduction was greater than $10,000, when the average is calculated using returns from filers who claimed that deduction -- not from every filer. He bases his statement on the taxes paid by about one-third of the population, generally the more affluent one-third."
                    }
                ]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "Was Dustin Diamond  in a show called 'saved by the bell?'",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Dustin Diamond, who played goofy Screech on the popular 1990s sitcom \"Saved By the Bell,\""
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Had he ever been in Jail?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Yes",
                        "bool_explanation": "four-month sentence in mid-January 2016 for a barroom stabbing."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Was he alive at the end of his sentence?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Yes",
                        "bool_explanation": "Dustin Diamond, who played goofy Screech on the popular 1990s sitcom \"Saved By the Bell,\" was sprung from jail in april 2016"
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Was he alive at the time of the claim (14th October 2020)?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Yes",
                        "bool_explanation": "He appeared in a 2020 tv show called 'open'"
                    }
                ]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "Are there any figures for the number of people who attended the People’s Vote march on Saturday 19 October.",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Tagesschau reported the march as having “hundreds of thousands” of participants"
                    },
                    {
                        "answer": "Deutsche Welle opted for “tens of thousands” of participants."
                    },
                    {
                        "answer": " Welt opted for “thousands” of participants. "
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "How many people attended the People’s March on Saturday 19 October?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "No answer could be found."
                    }
                ]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "Where does COVID-19 originate from?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "The short answer is that we don’t know for sure yet. Scientists do agree that COVID-19 is caused by a coronavirus from an animal (1,2). COVID-19 is a zoonosis, a human disease of animal origin. However, the animal source of SARS-CoV-2, the virus behind the COVID-19 pandemic, has not yet been confirmed. It is likely to have its ancestral origins in a bat species (1,2) but it probably reached humans through an intermediary species (pangolins have been suggested) (3,4), or mutated within humans to be able to be transmitted between people and cause disease (3). This is a priority area for research but it is important to note that subsequent transmission of COVID-19 is from person to person. It is transmission between people that has spread the disease globally."
                    },
                    {
                        "answer": "The novel coronavirus originated from the Hunan seafood market at Wuhan, China where bats, snakes, raccoon dogs, palm civets, and other animals are sold, and rapidly spread up to 109 countries. The zoonotic source of SARS-CoV-2 is not confirmed, however, sequence-based analysis suggested bats as the key reservoir. "
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Was COVID-19 made in a laboratory? ",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "No",
                        "bool_explanation": "Our analyses clearly show that SARS-CoV-2 is not a laboratory construct or a purposefully manipulated virus."
                    },
                    {
                        "answer": "No",
                        "bool_explanation_second": "We have exactly zero evidence or data of this having any connection to a lab."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Why was the US Army lab at Fort Detrick, Maryland, shut down?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Safety concerns at a prominent military germ lab have led the government to shut down research involving dangerous microbes like the Ebola virus.\n\n“Research is currently on hold,” the United States Army Medical Research Institute of Infectious Diseases, in Fort Detrick, Md., said in a statement on Friday. The shutdown is likely to last months, Caree Vander Linden, a spokeswoman, said in an interview.\n\nThe statement said the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention decided to issue a “cease and desist order” last month to halt the research at Fort Detrick because the center did not have “sufficient systems in place to decontaminate wastewater” from its highest-security labs.\n\nBut there has been no threat to public health, no injuries to employees and no leaks of dangerous material outside the laboratory, Ms. Vander Linden said.\n\nIn the statement, the C.D.C. cited “national security reasons” as the rationale for not releasing information about its decision."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Did the US Army lab at Fort Detrick, Maryland, reopen?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Yes",
                        "bool_explanation": "The Centers for Disease Control and Prevention restored full operating capability to all U.S. Army Medical Research Institute of Infectious Diseases (USAMRIID) labs at Fort Detrick, Maryland, last week following a shutdown last July of some high-level facilities out of safety concerns.\n\nThe CDC cleared USAMRIID's Level 3 and 4 laboratories -- those where the world's most dangerous pathogens are studied -- for full operations March 27. The labs had been operating under partial capacity since last November, following a cease-and-desist order issued last July by the CDC over lapses in biosafety standards."
                    }
                ]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "Are MRC-5 Cells used in all vaccines?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "nine vaccines containing MRC-5 authorized in the United States,"
                    },
                    {
                        "answer": "14 vaccines containing MRC-5 authorized in Canada,"
                    },
                    {
                        "answer": "Six vaccines containing MRC-5 authorized in Australia,"
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Are MSC-5 cells human cells?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "in total only two fetuses, both obtained from abortions done by maternal choice, have given rise to the human cell strains used in vaccine development"
                    }
                ]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "What is Load Shedding?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "This involves planned rolling blackouts on a rotating schedule throughout the country to avoid total power system failure."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Was there load shedding in the six months between August 2015 to February 2016?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Yes",
                        "bool_explanation": "According to a press release on January 29th 2016, the was a load shedding incidence 136 days before. Which puts it at 14 September 2015."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Has there been load shedding in South Africa since August 2015?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Yes",
                        "bool_explanation": "A load shedding incident occurred 136 days prior, according to a press release issued on January 29th, 2016. This puts the date at September 14, 2015."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Will load shedding continue in South Africa?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": " Eskom also wishes to remind South Africans that there is an increased possibility of loadshedding over the next 18 months as we are conducting critical maintenance to restore the ageing plant to good health.        "
                    }
                ]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "What is the sanitation coverage for 2019 in Kenya?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Table 2.1: Progress on Key Performance Indicators\nWater Coverage, % 57 59\nDrinking Water Quality, % 95 96\nHours of Supply, hrs/day 13 14\nNon- Revenue Water, % 41 43\nMetering Ratio, % 95 94\nStaff Productivity, Staff per 1000 Connections 7 7\nPersonnel expenditure as % of O+M Costs, % 50 50\nRevenue Collection Efficiency, % 94 92\nO+M Cost Coverage, % 99 105\nSewered Sanitation Coverage, % * 16 17\nSanitation Coverage, % * 80 81\nTrend\nSector Benchmarks: good acceptable not acceptable benchmark varies "
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Was there a drop in sanitation coverage in 2019 in Kenya ?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "The report does note there has been a decline in coverage as the population rose rapidly, outpacing investment in infrastructure."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Did Sanitation coverage drop from 25% to 16% in Kenya 2020 ? ",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "No answer could be found."
                    }
                ]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "Did Donald Trump tweet in 2009, \"Obama’s handling of this whole [H1N1] pandemic has been terrible! As President, ALL responsibility becomes yours during a crisis like this, whether or not you’re entirely to blame. John McCain, and myself for that matter myself, would never let thousands of Americans die from a pandemic while in office\"?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "The tweet does not appear on Factbase, which showcases deleted tweets made by Donald Trump."
                    },
                    {
                        "answer": "The tweet does not appear in Donald Trump's archives. "
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "What was the character limit on Twitter in 2009?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "140 characters"
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "How many characters are in the claim tweet?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "297"
                    }
                ]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "Where did the original statement come from?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "On June 1st 2020, Alberto Zangrillo, the head of San Raffaele Hospital in Milan, claimed that coronavirus is losing its potency and had become much less lethal."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "How did the WHO react to the claim?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "The World Health Organization stresses that the new coronavirus has not suddenly become less pathogenic, following claims by a leading Italian doctor that COVID-19 had lost some of its potency. \"We need to be exceptionally careful not to create a sense that, all of a sudden, the virus, by its own volition, has now decided to be less pathogenic. It is not the case at all,\" WHO emergencies director Michael Ryan tells a virtual press briefing."
                    }
                ]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "What are Mercenaries?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Private military\ncontractors although the term ‘‘mercenary’’ takes on a number of definitions under international legal\ninstruments, but its use is not reserved for legal discourse. Instead, the ‘‘mercenary’’\nlabel is frequently ‘‘applied to express the speaker’s disapproval, rather than to\ndescribe an individual satisfying the specific criteria under international law’’,"
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Did Russia claim its ''private military contractors'' were not involved in any combat?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Yes",
                        "bool_explanation": "The president of Russia said, “Look, as for the private companies, including the private security companies under which the people you have mentioned were operating – this is not the Russian state, and they are not engaged in combat.”"
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "What is the date of the caim?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "20th June 2019."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Is there any evidence of Russian Private Military Contractors taking part in any combat situations around the time of the claim?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Images show contract soldiers who work for Wagner PMC in combat in both Donbas and Syria"
                    },
                    {
                        "answer": "Photos show Russian military instructors in Syria. "
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Is there evidence to show that Russian Mercenaries  engaged in Combat ?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Recently a number of photos and videos appeared online depicting Russian men working for a \"PMC\" called Vega, training pro-Assad militia members. Recent reports from Syrian rebels fighting around Idlib and northern Hama have also mentioned clashes with Russian mercenaries, although these cannot always be confirmed."
                    }
                ]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "Do photos exist of the congregation at John Lewis' funeral and does the picture whether the congregation was socially distanced?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "There is a picture of the congregation and it clearly shows the congregation socially distancing."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Did the funeral for John Lewis follow socially distancing guidelines?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "The Lewis family made a statement prior to the funeral that spoke about social distancing that said, \"Even under normal circumstances, there simply is not a church big enough to hold all the people who knew and loved Rep.Lewis, but these difficult times make it especially challenging to accommodate everyone who wants to attend his services Though Ebenezer Baptist Church can fit a sizable number of people under ordinary circumstances, due to precautions necessary during the pandemic, the church will only accommodate 240 people in total, due to social distancing precautions. Half of those seats will be occupied by Rep. Lewis’s family and relatives, as it should be, and by the time congressional dignitaries and other friends are added, it leaves very little wiggle room to offer additional participants a chance to attend.\"\n\n“Given the seriousness of the pandemic, the Lewis family wants people to protect their health, and encourages people who want to attend to consider organizing virtual John Lewis Love events in their homes to watch his funeral services tomorrow.\""
                    }
                ]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "What were the ministers charged with?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "In 2015 the anti-corruption agency charged former transport cabinet secretary Michael Kamau in court for failing to comply with procurement laws."
                    },
                    {
                        "answer": "Former lands minister Charity Ngilu was also charged, for “breach of trust” by a public official."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Were they aquitted?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Yes",
                        "bool_explanation": "They were both acquitted after successfully challenging the composition of the ethics agency. But Kamau was back in court in April 2019, on the same charges."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Were Charity Ngilu or Michael Kamau back in court? ",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "In April 2019, Michael Kamau was back in court on the same charges. "
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Did Michael Kamau go to court?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Yes",
                        "bool_explanation": "He first appeared in court in 2016 for violating procurement laws."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Why was Charity Ngilu acquitted? ",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "The court on Monday dropped the case following a Court of Appeal order that declared the trial unconstitutional."
                    }
                ]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "Did President Trump fully cooperate with the investigation into Russian interference in the 2016 U.S. presidential campaign?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "The Mueller report found that President Trump \" engaged in a second phase of conduct, involving public attacks on the investigation, non-public efforts to control it, and efforts in both public and private to encourage witnesses not to cooperate with the investigation.\" "
                    },
                    {
                        "answer": "The Mueller report noted that they requested an in-person interview with President Trump, which had been sought for more than a year.\n\n\"After extensive discussions with the Department of Justice about\nthe Special Counsel's objective of securing the President's testimony, these accommodations\nincluded the submissions of written questions to the President on certain Russia-related topics.\"\n\nThe written responses from Trump were received in late November 2018; however, the responses were told to be insufficient in several respects.\n\nThe report \"... noted, among other things, that the President stated on more than 30 occasions that he \"does not 'recall' or 'remember' or have an ' independent recollection\"' of information called for by the questions. 6 Other answers were \"incomplete or imprecise.\" 7 The written responses, we informed counsel,\n\"demonstrate the inadequacy of the written format, as we have had no opportunity to ask follow-up questions that would ensure complete answers and potentially refresh your client's recollection or clarify the extent or nature of his lack of recollection.\"8 We again requested an in-person interview, limited to certain topics, advising the President's counsel that \"[t]his is the President's opportunity to voluntarily provide us with information for us to evaluate in the context of all of the evidence we have gathered.\"9 The President declined. 10\""
                    }
                ]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "Did Spain asked money from the UK to cover its debts ?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "There is  no evidence that Spain  asked for money from the UK to cover its debts. "
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "How much does Spain receives from EU budget ?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Spain received just under €2 billion—around 0.2% of the total value of its debt."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "How is the EU budget spent?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "The long-term budget sets out the EU's long-term spending priorities and limits.\n\nThe EU budget finances activities ranging from developing rural areas and conserving the environment to protecting external borders and promoting human rights. The Commission, the Council and Parliament all have a say in determining the size of the budget and how it is allocated. But it is the Commission that is responsible for spending. The EU countries and the Commission share responsibility for about 80% of the budget. Drafting the budget\nThe budget is decided jointly by the Commission, the Council and Parliament. The Commission submits a draft to the Council and Parliament for their consideration. They can make changes; if they disagree, they have to work out a compromise.\n\nEach year’s budget sets out the amounts agreed in advance according to a plan known as the multiannual financial framework. This enables the EU to plan its funding programmes effectively for several years in advance. The current framework runs from 2014 to 2020. Managing EU funds\nThe ultimate responsibility for allocating the budget lies with the Commission. However, national governments manage about 80% of EU funds. Where undue payments have been made, the Commission works with the EU countries concerned to recover the money. To ensure transparency, organisations and companies that receive EU funding are on public record."
                    }
                ]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "Did Russia Pay the Taliban  Bounties to Kill US Troops in Afghanistan? \n",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Some of Trump’s senior intelligence officials viewed information about the bounties as credible enough to warn the Defense Department and allies, so they could ensure that they had protective measures for their forces in Afghanistan, and to begin developing options for a response to Russia, national security adviser Robert C. O’Brien has said. O’Brien also said the CIA has asked the Justice Department to open a leak investigation into the matter."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Was there any White House intelligence report about a possible Russian-bounty payment to Taliban ? ",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Recent intelligence reports indicating that Russian bounties paid to the Taliban to kill U.S. troops have bolstered American and Afghan officials' long-held allegations that Moscow has been engaged in clandestine operations to undermine the U.S. mission in Afghanistan. Russia’s support for the Taliban, however, has largely been tactical in nature. Both Washington and Moscow ultimately have a converging strategic interest in a relatively stable Afghanistan without a long-term U.S. presence that will not be a haven for transnational terrorists. USIP’s Andrew Wilder looks at what this means for the decades-long Afghan conflict."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Why did Russia offer bounty or provided tactical-level support to the Taliban, in Afghanistan?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Russia has several reasons for providing tactical-level support to the Taliban. The first is simply the irresistible temptation to make life more difficult for the United States and NATO allies at relatively little cost, similar to some of the asymmetric tactics Moscow is using to challenge Washington in other conflicts."
                    }
                ]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "When was Bill Murray born and how old is he?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "September 21, 1950, 72 years old."
                    }
                ]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "Is Lebron James quoted as saying he wants nothing to do with white people?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "The quote is taken out of context, The NBA legend was explaining what was in his mind as a 14-year-old starting at a mostly-white high school.\n\nThe quote comes from a segment of the HBO show \"The Shop\", which features \"unfiltered conversation and debate from the biggest names in sports and entertainment\" as they visit barbershops around the country.\n\nIn the segment quoted in the meme, James said he had never been around white people until he was 14 and transferred to a mostly-white school. He explained how it took him \"a little time to adjust to it\":\n\nI went to an all white high school, a Catholic high school. So, like, when I first went to the 9th grade and to high school I was on some, like, I'm not f**king with white people, like, I was so institutionalized, growing up in the hood it's like they don't f**k with us. They don't want us to succeed. The hierarchy and then we're here, like, matter fact, we're underneath this chair. So, I'm like going to this school to play ball and that's it. I don't want nothing to do with white people. I don't believe that they want anything to do with me. I don't want no, It's me and my boys be going to high school together and we're here to hoop. So, that was like my initial thoughts and intitial shock to like white America when I was 14 years old, for the first time in my life."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "When LeBron James said 'He Wants Nothing To Do With White People' was he being racist?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "No",
                        "bool_explanation": "He was talking the transition from his neighbourhood hood to a catholic high school, being around all white people for the first time."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "What exactly did he say in relation to the claims quote?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "''I dont want nothing to do with white people. I dont believe they want anything to do with me. I dont want no white friends. its me and my boys''"
                    }
                ]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "What is Leukoderma otherwise known as ?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Vitiligo"
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "What causes vitiligo?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Although multiple hypotheses have been suggested as potential triggers that cause vitiligo, studies strongly imply that changes in the immune system are responsible for the condition.[1][10] Vitiligo has been proposed to be a multifactorial disease with genetic susceptibility and environmental factors both thought to play a role.[1]\n\nThe National Institutes of Health states that some believe that sunburns can cause or exacerbate the condition, but that this idea is not well-supported by good evidence.[11]"
                    }
                ]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "What website did the claim come from?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "bustatroll.org"
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "What type of website is bustatroll.org?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "The website has obvious hints that it is of a satirical nature.\n\nI.e., the article is inked \"Confederate Flag Satire to Rile the Taters.\"\n\nAdditionally, the website includes an image with the text \"SATIRE S RATED.\""
                    }
                ]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "Does John Cornyn's campaign ad guarantee insurers will be made to sell plans to any patient with pre-existing conditions?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Yes",
                        "bool_explanation": "It says, ''with John Cornyn's plan, they will be covered''"
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "How does he plan to guarantee pre-existing conditions are accepted for health insurance?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "the Better Care Reconciliation Act (BCRA)"
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Does the better-care-reconciliation-act affect low cost protection to pre-existing conditions?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Yes",
                        "bool_explanation": "It would affect a specific group of people who meet the following criteria: lives in a state that seeks this waiver; has a lapse in health coverage for longer than 63 days; has a preexisting condition; "
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "How would it affect those with Pre-existing conditions?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "though the bill explicitly prohibits waivers for preexisting conditions, health analysts say waiving the essential health benefits package and eliminating the three guardrail requirements could weaken the types of services covered for people with preexisting conditions."
                    }
                ]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "What is the recent total alcohol consumption per capita in South Africa?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "In a 2016 most recent report, South Africa's total alcohol per capita (15+) consumption, drinkers only (in litres of pure\nalcohol) was:\n\n29.9 litres (Both sexes (15+))"
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Did any other countries have a higher level of consumption among drinkers?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Yes",
                        "bool_explanation": "Tunisia at 36.6 litres Both sexes (15+)\n\nEswatini at 34.4 litres Both sexes (15+)\n\nNamibia at 32.4 litres Both sexes (15+)"
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Where did South Africa rank in alcohol consumption?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "In 2016, South Africa ranked ninth out of 53 African countries, with 9.3 litres of pure alcohol per person."
                    }
                ]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "When did Nigeria gain independence?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "in October 1960"
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "What was the approximate population of Nigeria in 1960?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Data from the World Bank and the UN’s department of economic and social affairs shows Nigeria’s population was 45.1 million in 1960.\n\nThat estimate was specifically for 1 July 1960, three months before independence day,"
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "How accurate is this estimate?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Nigeria’s population figures have historically been controversial, with resource allocation identified as a key reason for this.\n\nGbolahan Oni is professor of demography and social statistics at Covenant University in southwestern Nigeria. He told Africa Check that only United Nations and World Bank population estimates should be relied on when looking at previous years."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "What was Nigeria's urban population in 1960?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "A report was prepared by the UN’s department of economic and social affairs. Spoorenberg is the population affairs officer in the department’s population estimates and projection section. \n\nThe report estimates Nigeria’s 1960 urban population at 6.96 million. "
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "How is \"urban\" defined in this context?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Countries define urban in different ways, the UN’s population division says. Most – “nearly two thirds” – use an administrative definition “but almost all of them add an element such as population size, density, economic occupation or urban functions” to characterise urban areas.\n\nDenmark and Iceland, for example, define urban locals as only 200 inhabitants or more, while the Netherlands and Nigeria have a threshold of 20,000.\n"
                    }
                ]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "Does introduction of cellular telecommunications or radio technologies caused outbreaks of disease?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "There is no pattern linking outbreaks of disease with cellular telecommunications or radio technologies. Experts have also highlighted the lack of evidence to suggest cellular technology causes adverse health impacts."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "What are the causes of outbreaks of disease?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "In epidemiology, an outbreak is a sudden increase in occurrences of a disease when cases are in excess of normal expectancy for the location or season. It may affect a small and localized group or impact upon thousands of people across an entire continent. The number of cases varies according to the disease-causing agent, and the size and type of previous and existing exposure to the agent. Outbreaks include many epidemics, which term is normally only for infectious diseases, as well as diseases with an environmental origin, such as a water or foodborne disease. They may affect a region in a country or a group of countries. Pandemics are near-global disease outbreaks when multiple and various countries around the Earth are soon infected."
                    }
                ]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "Does Japan Import any goods from USA?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Japan was the United States' 4th largest goods export market in 2019.\n \nU.S. goods exports to Japan in 2019 were $74.7 billion, down 0.8% ($576 million) from 2018 but up 46% from 2009.  U.S. exports to Japan account for 4.5% of overall U.S. exports in 2019.\n \nThe top export categories (2-digit HS) in 2019 were: mineral fuels ($9.3 billion), aircraft ($8.8 billion), optical and medical instruments ($7.1 billion), machinery ($7.0 billion), and electrical machinery ($4.6 billion).\n \nU.S. total exports of agricultural products to Japan totaled $12 billion in 2019, our 4th largest agricultural export market. Leading domestic export categories include: corn ($2.0 billion), beef & beef products ($2.0 billion), pork & pork products ($1.5 billion), soybeans ($965 million), and wheat ($608 million).\n \nU.S. exports of services to Japan were an estimated $48.7 billion in 2019, 7.7% ($3.5 billion) more than 2018, but 28% greater than 2009 levels.  Leading services exports from the U.S. to Japan were in the travel, transport, and intellectual property (trademarks and computer software) sectors."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Does Japan export any goods to USA?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Japan was the United States' 4th largest supplier of goods imports in 2019.\n \nU.S. goods imports from Japan totaled $143.6 billion in 2019, up 0.9% ($1.2 billion) from 2018, and up 50% from 2009.  U.S. imports from Japan account for 5.7% of overall U.S. imports in 2019.\n \nThe top import categories (2-digit HS) in 2019 were: vehicles ($49 billion), machinery ($34 billion), electrical machinery ($17 billion), optical and medical instruments ($7.0 billion), and pharmaceuticals ($4.3 billion).\n \nU.S. total imports of agricultural products from Japan totaled $767 million in 2019. Leading categories include: wine and beer ($78 million), snack foods ($70 million), tea, including herbal ($63 million), other vegetable oils ($49 million), and processed fruit & vegetables ($35 million).\n \nU.S. imports of services from Japan were an estimated $36.0 billion in 2019, 3.6% ($1.3 billion) more than 2018, and 69% greater than 2009 levels.  Leading services imports from Japan to the U.S. were in the intellectual property (industrial processes), transport, and travel sectors."
                    }
                ]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "Did Biden condemn the violence and looting that took place in Kenosha, Wisconsin by 27th August 2020?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Biden has condemned violent protesters in Kenosha and elsewhere. In a video released on Twitter.\n\nBiden said: “Burning down communities is not protest, it’s needless violence—violence that endangers lives, violence that guts businesses, and shutters businesses that serve the community. That’s wrong.”"
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "What date did Biden condemn the violence and looting?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Wednesday 26th August 2020."
                    }
                ]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "What is the date of the claim?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "17th March 2021."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "At the time of the claim was there evidence to support the use of ivermectin to prevent or treat COVID-19?\n",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "The FDA had not reviewed data to support use of ivermectin in COVID-19 patients to treat or to prevent COVID-19; however, some initial research was underway."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "At the time of the claim was there any evidence that Hydroxychloroquine  could be used to treat of cure Covid 19?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "The National Essential Medicines List (NEMLC) COVID-19 subcommittee\nrecommend against using\nthe following drugs to treat patients with COVID-19 outside of a clinical trial:\n Chloroquine or hydroxychloroquine"
                    }
                ]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "How many people attended Trumps Tulsa Rally ?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Just fewer than 6,200 people attended President Donald Trump’s rally in Tulsa, Oklahoma, the Tulsa Fire Department said"
                    },
                    {
                        "answer": "Tulsa fire department says just under 6,200 people attended Trump rally"
                    }
                ]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "When was this claim made?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "10/07/2020"
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "What is Mahashvratri?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "The Great night of lord Shiva is called as Maha Shiv Ratri. It occurs in the luni-solar month of the Hindu calendar, on the month's 13th night/14th day prior to spring."
                    },
                    {
                        "answer": "Mahashivratri (also known as Shivaratri) is a Hindu festival dedicated to Shiva, who destroys the universe, one of the deities of the Hindu Trinity."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "When was Mahashvratri celebrated in 2020?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "falls on 21st February this year"
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Was Mahashvratri observed in Karachi in 2020?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Yes",
                        "bool_explanation": "There is video evidence shared on Twitter. "
                    },
                    {
                        "answer": "Yes",
                        "bool_explanation_second": "Danish Kaneria, a Pakistani cricketer, tweeted about Mahashvratri celebrations in Karachi, Pakistan, in 2020."
                    }
                ]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "Is Cherie Blair representing Shamima Begum ?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Cherie Blairs office confirmed to fact checking website direct that she is not and has never represented Begum."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Did Cherie Blair represented Shamima Begum?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Cherie Blair’s office confirmed to us that neither she nor her law firm represent or have ever represented Shamima Begum.\n\nThe solicitor who represented Ms Begum’s family, Tasnime Akunjee, told Full Fact that he was working under the understanding that she was still in the al-Roj camp in Syria.\n\nHe said that neither her family nor her lawyer, Gareth Peirce, were “aware of her return or imminent return”.\n\nGareth Peirce’s law firm did not respond to Full Fact’s request for comment."
                    }
                ]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "Did any other presidential administration help the auto industry?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Yes",
                        "bool_explanation": "former President George W. Bush defended his decision to start the bailout of the auto industry at the end of his final term. \"I'd do it again,\" Bush said. In his 2010 book, Bush called the bailout \"the only option.\" The latest comment comes on the heels of Obama's State of the Union address where he proclaimed \"the U.S. auto industry is back.\""
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "How did the Obama-Biden administration help the auto industry?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Obama has proudly trumpeted the $85 billion bailouts of General Motors Co. and Chrysler Group LLC as a success story while the U.S. auto industry continues its dramatic recovery."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Who helped bail out the auto industry? ",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "The Bush and Obama administrations loaned the auto industry, including GM and Chrysler, which is now controlled by Italy’s Fiat, $80 billion to avoid the collapse of the industry that they felt would result in the loss of millions of U.S. jobs."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Did the bailout save autoworker jobs in Michigan?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Yes",
                        "bool_explanation": "The Center for Automotive Research (CAR) in Ann Arbor, Michigan, estimated in its study that the bailout saved a lot of jobs, even crediting for a rebound of the industry in 2010 after the initial fallout."
                    }
                ]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "When was this claim made?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "20/09/2020"
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "When is the US election in 2020?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Election Day is November 3, 2020."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Would 30 to 40% of Americans have voted by October 1st, 2020, in the US Election?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "No answer could be found."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "When does early voting begin in the U.S.?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Many states have different dates for early voting. \n\nIn California, for example, early voting begins 29 days before the election.\n\nWhilst, Louisiana it is Fourteen days before election. \n\nIn Michigan, you can do in-person absentee voting during the 40 days before an election."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "How many Americans voted early in the 2016 presidential election by October 1st? ",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "No answer could be found."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "How many Americans voted early in the 2016 presidential election by October 2nd?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "By October 2nd, 2016, at least 74,836 people will have voted in the 2016 election as of this weekend."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "What percentage of voters voted before election day in 2016?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "41%"
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "How many states offer early voting?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Forty-five states and the District of Columbia offer early in-person voting (including states with all-mail elections). Delaware has enacted early voting but it will not be in place until 2022. Five states do not offer pre-Election Day in-person voting options: Connecticut, Mississippi, Missouri, New Hampshire, and South Carolina."
                    }
                ]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "Is Tom Hanks still alive?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Yes",
                        "bool_explanation": "Wiki page is up to date and does not mention him dying."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Where did the claim originate?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "https://the-daily-star.com/breaking-coronavirus-claims-life-of-tom-hanks/"
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "What is known about https://the-daily-star.com/ ?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "At the bottom of the page for the story it states:\n\n\"Disclaimer: This is satire.\""
                    }
                ]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "How much of Africa's electricity is generated by Eskom? ",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "No answer could be found."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "How much electricity did Eskom sell to Africa in 2018/2019? ",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "208,319 GWh between 1 April 2018 to 31 March 2019. "
                    }
                ]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "What is the basis for this claim?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "The argument comes from the way Medicare currently reimburses hospitals, at 87 cents for every dollar spent on health care. which could be removed under the democrats plan."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "What was the currant health system called?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Medicare for all."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Under the democrats plans would Hospitals close?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Some hospitals, especially struggling rural centers, may close virtually overnight, according to policy experts."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Would doctors and hospital staff lose their jobs under democratic plans?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Some hospitals, may try to offset the steep cuts by laying off  workers or abandoning lower-paying services like mental health."
                    }
                ]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "What was Nigeria's total debt?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "According to the Debt Management Office, Nigeria’s total debt was N12.6 trillion in December 2015, N17.36 trillion in December 2016 and N21.73 trillion in December 2017."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "What was the capital expenditure during this same period?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "In 2016, capital expenditure was N1.59 trillion (including share of capital in statutory transfers was N1.75 trillion). But media reports say the amount disbursed for capital projects that year was N1.2 trillion. We have not yet been able to verify this figure as some of this rolled over into 2017.\n\nIn 2017, the budgeted capital expenditure was N2,178 trillion, while development projects for the year were reported in the media as using N1.6 trillion. But in the absence of an official budget performance report, we are unable to verify Obi’s number"
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "What was the capital expenditure for 2016?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Capital Expenditure (excluding Share of\nCapital in Statutory Transfers) = N1.59 trillion\n– Capital Expenditure (including share of\ncapital expenditure in Statutory Transfer) = N1.75 trillion"
                    },
                    {
                        "answer": "The Federal Government said it released a total of N1.2tn to finance capital projects as contained in the 2016 budget.\n\nThe figure was released by the Ministry of Finance through a statement issued by the Director of Information, Salisu Dambatta."
                    },
                    {
                        "answer": "Since the 2016 budget was also implemented in the 2017 calendar year, we are yet to know how much is total amount spent on capital expenditure."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "What was the capital expenditure for 2017?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": " Expenditure while the sum of =N=2,177,866,775,867\n(Two Trillion, One Hundred and Seventy-Seven Billion, Eight-Hundred and Sixty-Six\nMillion, Seven Hundred and Seventy-Five Thousand, Eight Hundred and Sixty-Seven\nNaira) only, is for contribution to the Development Fund for Capital Expenditure\n(exclusive of capital expenditure in Statutory Transfers) for the year ending on the\n31st December, 2017."
                    },
                    {
                        "answer": "The Federal Government has announced that a total of N1.6 trillion (N1,580,270,755,084.44) capital cost was released to Ministries, Departments and Agencies for the 2017 federal budget"
                    }
                ]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "Who made this claim?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Donald J. Trump.\n"
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "What did he make this claim in relation to?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "His implementation of trade tariffs on china.",
                        "bool_explanation": "His implementation of trade tariffs on china."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Has Trump made similar claims prior to this one?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Yes",
                        "bool_explanation": "This is not the first time President Trump has boasted about the damage the trade war has inflicted on China. \"They've lost two and a half million jobs in a very short period of time,\" he said last week."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Has China confirmed any job losses due to Trumps trade tariffs?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "There is no official Chinese data specifically on job losses as a result of the US-China trade war,"
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Are there any surveys about job losses in China ",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "economic surveys carried out by two Chinese banks suggest a range of 1.2 to 1.9 million jobs were impacted by the trade war in the industrial sector."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Can all the job losses seen in the economic surveys be attributed to Trumps Trade tariffs?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Job losses in manufacturing have been part of a longer-term trend as China moves towards a more service-based economy with the creation of jobs in finance and technology, and this transition began even before the trade war started."
                    }
                ]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "Did Britain import COVID-19 tests from China?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "No",
                        "bool_explanation": "There were no mentions of the tests coming from china, they came from a Luxembourg based laboratory company, Eurofins"
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Were they contaminated with Covid-19?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Yes",
                        "bool_explanation": ", Eurofins -- a Luxembourg-based laboratory and testing company -- informed British laboratories that parts of the testing kits called “probers and primers” that have been delivered to them were contaminated with the virus. "
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Were the supplied COVID-19 test kits from China?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "No",
                        "bool_explanation": "Eurofins, a company based in Luxembourg"
                    }
                ]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "How were voting machines set up for the primaries?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Voting machines were set up so that the republican and democratic primary votes were on separate machines. The machines would be allocated to reflect how many democrat or republican voters were in  a particular area. So some had equal numbers while others would have mostly democratic or mostly republican machines."
                    }
                ]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "How much money did the Australian Red Cross give given out to bushfire victims as of the 16/02/2020 ?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "The Australian Red Cross had paid $32 million in emergency grants, according to a media release dated February 13. The charity also announced on February 3 that it was providing an additional $10,000 to extend the amount available to $20,000 as part of its immediate assistance."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Did the charity distributed only $7 million “in $10,000 lots” ?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": " The charity also announced on February 3 that it was providing an additional $10,000 to extend the amount available to $20,000 as part of its immediate assistance."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Did the charity distribute only $7 million “in $10,000 lots” ?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": " The charity also announced on February 3 that it was providing an additional $10,000 to extend the amount available to $20,000 as part of its immediate assistance."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "What other grants have the red cross made available?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "The Red Cross also provides a $7500 injury grant for people “who have spent more than two days in hospital “as a direct result of bushfires” and a primary residence repair grant of $5000 for “homeowners whose homes have been structurally damaged”. "
                    }
                ]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "What image is this referring to?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "a black and white image showing a man being  apprehended by two police officers."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Is this man Bernie Sanders?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Yes",
                        "bool_explanation": "This is a photo of Bernie Sanders from 1963"
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "What was really happening in the photo?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "In the early 1960s, protests over segregation in the Englewood area raged over mobile classrooms dubbed \"Willis Wagons,\" named for then-Chicago Schools Superintendent Benjamin Willis. Critics charged that the trailers kept black children in the area instead of sending them to white schools. Bernie Sanders was protesting this and was arrested by police "
                    }
                ]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "Which law does the claim relate to?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Hong Kong National Security law."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "What is included in the Hong Kong National Security Law?\n",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Under its provisions, anyone believed to be carrying out terrorism, separatism, subversion of state power and collusion with foreign forces could face life in prison."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Have Foreign countries condemned the law?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "The U.S. Congress quickly passed legislation authorizing sanctions against Hong Kong police and Chinese Communist Party leaders."
                    },
                    {
                        "answer": "Secretary of State Mike Pompeo denounced the law as “draconian.”"
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "What has been said in the Hong Kong Press?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "t pro-democracy activists said no part of Hong Kong speech is safe.\n\n“The reality is, under the Hong Kong national security law, every sentence said by every person at every moment could touch the red line and be said as violating the law,” Benny Tai, a legal scholar in Hong Kong, told the Hong Kong Free Press"
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "How would the law be enforced?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "In implementing the national security law for Hong Kong, police will have sweeping authority that allows them to take actions including conducting searches without a warrant, restricting suspects from leaving the city, and intercepting communications.\n\nHong Kong’s government issued the details of Article 43 in the city’s national security law on Monday night, which outlines the measures that the police force can take to implement the legislation in the city.\n\nAccording to the rules, police may be authorized to conduct searches for evidence without a warrant in “exceptional circumstances.” Police may also apply for a warrant that requires a person suspected of violating the national security law to surrender their travel documents, thus restricting them from leaving Hong Kong.\n\nAdditionally, under the rules, written notices or restraining orders may be issued to freeze or confiscate property if there are “reasonable grounds” to suspect that the property is related to an offense endangering national security.\n\nPlatforms and publishers, as well as internet service providers, may also be ordered to take down electronic messages published that are “likely to constitute an offence endangering national security or is likely to cause the occurrence of an offence endangering national security.”\n\nService providers who do not comply with such requests could face fines of up to 100,000 Hong Kong dollars ($12,903) and receive jail terms of six months.\n\nIndividuals who post such messages may also be asked to remove the message, or face similar fines and a jail term of one year."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Is free speech in Hong Kong safe?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Pro-democracy legal scholar Benny Tai said the statement meant that people can no longer chant “Liberate Hong Kong, revolution of our times.” He said the government could ban this slogan today, and prohibit other chants tomorrow.\n\n“The reality is, under the Hong Kong national security law, every sentence said by every person at every moment could touch the red line and be said as violating the law. How could the national security law only targets a small group of people,” Tai said."
                    }
                ]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "Could the number of arrests be incorrect?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Yes",
                        "bool_explanation": "Those arrested can have more than one type of conviction or pending charge so the total number of charges and convictions is greater than the total number of arrestees; ICE counts an immigrant with a prior criminal conviction and pending criminal charges only in the criminal conviction category."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "How many people has ICE arrested in the last two years?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "158,581 arrests in 2018\n\n143,470 arrests in 2017"
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "When was this claim made? ",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "02/03/2019"
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "What were the most common crimes committed by immigrants?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Traffic Offences - DUI\nDangerous Drugs\nTraffic Offences\nImmigration \nAssault "
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "How many of the total number of arrests in the past 2 years were repeat offenders / people charged with more than 1 crime?\n(158,581 in 2018 & 143,470 in 2017)",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "No answer could be found."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Of the 302,051 arrests in the past 2 years how many people were convicted/found guilty?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "No answer could be found."
                    }
                ]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "Has Trumps 2020 budget made cuts to funding for health care?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Trump’s fiscal year 2020 budget proposal asks for $87.1 billion in discretionary funding for the health department. That’s a 12 percent decrease from 2019."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "What tax cuts does the claim refer to?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "2017 Tax Cuts and Jobs Act"
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Will only Billionaires benefit from the tax cuts?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "analysis of the 2017 Tax Cuts and Jobs Act found that every income group is expected to pay less in taxes in 2019, but the benefits of the tax bill flow disproportionately to wealthier taxpayers. Some of the individual tax cuts phase out in 2025 for lower-earning income groups. By 2027, every income group below $75,000 sees a tax increase, our analysis said.\n\nWhile spending cuts can be seen as a way to compensate for tax cuts, there isn’t a direct link between the proposed health care cuts and the recently passed tax law, experts told us.\n\n\"The existence of tax cuts may put more pressure to cut Medicare and Medicaid,\" Goldwein said. \"But any relationship is indirect.\""
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Is there a direct link to proposed health care cuts to compensate for tax cuts?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "No answer could be found."
                    }
                ]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "Which study stated that 68% of those unemployed are making more on unemployment than they did on the job?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "National Bureau of Economic Research"
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Have other studies seen the same effect?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Yes",
                        "bool_explanation": "A Yale University research study on the effect of the $600 benefit, published on July 14, 2020, discovered that  \"The CARES Act expanded unemployment insurance (UI) benefits by providing a $600\nweekly payment in addition to state unemployment benefits. Most workers thus became eligible to receive unemployment benefits that exceed their weekly wages. It has been hypothesized\nthat such high benefits encourage employers to lay off workers and discourage workers from\nreturning to work.\""
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Are people who receive unemployment benefits more likely to look for work? ",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "A June 2020 analysis by the Chicago Federal Reserve found \"that the unemployed exert a high level of effort to find work. This is especially true for those receiving unemployment insurance benefits. Those who have exhausted their unemployment benefits search less intensely for work, but are also willing to accept work that pays considerably less than their prior job.\""
                    }
                ]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "Is vaccination mandatory in Canada?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Vaccination in Canada is only mandatory for students in Ontario, the country’s most populous province, and in the Atlantic province of New Brunswick. Nationwide, it is highly recommended.\n\nHowever, legislation in both provinces include exemption clauses based on medical, religious, or moral grounds. Neither law mentions the Hippocratic Oath or exceptions rooted in the “do no harm” doctrine.\n\nIncreasing vaccination coverage remains a goal for Canada outlined in the National Immunization Strategy."
                    }
                ]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "What does the Education MInister say?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "According to a Hindustan Times report, Education Minister Himanta Biswa Sarma said on June 7 that admission to universities, colleges and higher secondary schools in Assam will be free during the current academic year.\n\n"
                    },
                    {
                        "answer": "#AssamEduCare Extremely pleased to share GOA has made ALL admissions - from HS upto PG level including medical, engineering, polytechnic for academic year 2020-21 - absolutely free. Under stress due to #COVID19, this shall be big relief to families. All prospectus will be free."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Which students will be admitted to institutes for free?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "\"Students from the higher secondary to the postgraduate level, including medical, engineering and polytechnic students, will be admitted to institutes for free,\" Sarma was quoted as saying a day after the results for Class 10 state board examinations were announced only on online platforms."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "What other support will be available?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "It was also stated that the prospectus and admission forms will be available online free of cost. For those staying in hostels, the Education Department will also pay Rs 1,000 as monthly mess dues and an additional amount of Rs 1,000 will be provided to all students for buying textbooks.\n\nStudents who passed the Class 10 examinations last year will be given computers in their school and those who have cleared the test this year will get Rs 20,000 so that they can buy computers of their choice, Sarma said.\n\n"
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Will there be any hidden costs?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "No",
                        "bool_explanation": "Education Minister Himanta Biswa Sarma said there would be no hidden costs. "
                    }
                ]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "Were there two million people at the People’s Vote march on Saturday 19 October 2019, report by Sky News?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "There is no evidence of either Sky News or German TV reporting these figures. Crowd scientists at Manchester Metropolitan University have told us that 2 million is an implausible estimate. "
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "How many people attended the People’s Vote march on Saturday 19 October, 2019? ",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Based on the weight of evidence, the crowd at Saturday’s march was likely in the low-to-mid hundreds of thousands and certainly not in the millions."
                    }
                ]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "What is the GAC?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Michael Davitt Gaelic Athletic Club (GAC) in Swatragh"
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "What has a spokesperson for the club said?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "We would be happy for our premises to be used as a field hospital in the event that its [sic] needed in the impending onslaught from the coronavirus.”\n\n“We have the premises, location and facilities to offer a viable option for a field hospital,” the club spokesperson said."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Has any contact been made with the relevant authorities in this matter?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "In a letter (23 March 2020) on the club’s Facebook page, the Michael Davitt GAC Chairman, Cormac McCormack, responded directly to the article, stating that “no contact has yet been made with relevant authorities with regards to any proposals”. The letter says that the Club has not ruled out the potential use of the grounds in such a way, and that a consultation is ongoing with the local community and relevant Health Authorities, to establish how it may support the NHS during the COVID-19 crisis."
                    }
                ]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "What event lead up to this claim?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "The police officer-involved death of George Floyd on May 25, 2020, in Minneapolis led to a call for nationwide law enforcement reform as demonstrators denounced police brutality during protests that swept across the country last summer.\n\nIn New York, Governor Andrew Cuomo issued Executive Order 203 in June to direct local police agencies statewide to review their forces and develop plans to improve them.\n\nThe directive led the city of Ithaca, New York, in collaboration with Tompkins County, to release a recommendations report on Monday that reimagines its public safety and law enforcement."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "What does the claim say the police will be replaced with?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "A twitter user posted, \"My state is a black hole of stupidity. Ithaca (NY) Mayor Calls for Abolishing Police Dept, Replacing With 'Community Solution Workers'"
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "What does the Mayor say he is doing?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "The Ithaca Police Department would be replaced with a \"Department of Community Solutions and Public Safety.\"\n\nThe plan would have armed public safety workers focus on interrupting and solving serious crimes and unarmed community solution workers who focus on de-escalation."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "What kind of calls would these Community Solution Workers handle?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "\"IPD currently spends one third of its time responding to calls for service that essentially never lead to arrests,\" Myrick wrote in the report. \"Those calls, as well as a majority of patrol activity can and should be handled by unarmed Community Solution Workers well trained in de-escalation and service delivery. This will allow our new Public Safety Workers to focus on preventing, interrupting and solving serious crime.\""
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "How would this department receive funding?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "The proposed civilian-led department would receive funding the same way the IPD receives funding through locally funded sales tax and property tax, according to Myrick."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Has this been approved?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "No",
                        "bool_explanation": "The Common Council has to approve this proposal, and city leaders expect a vote by the end of march.\n\n"
                    }
                ]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "When was the standard gauge railway first proposed in Kenya?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "January 2009 (Only approximately 10 years before the claim was made and not 30 as stated in the claim)."
                    }
                ]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "Did Thomas Jefferson say, “When the people fear the government, there is tyranny. When the government fears the people, there is liberty.”?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "The quote was not found on the Papers of Thomas Jefferson website. "
                    },
                    {
                        "answer": "The quote was not found on the Jefferson Quotes & Family Letters website."
                    },
                    {
                        "answer": "No",
                        "bool_explanation_third": "It is deemed a spurious quotation by the Thomas Jefferson Foundation, which maintains his estate at Monticello."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Could the quote be in reference to something spoken by Thomas Jefferson?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Jefferson described the political parties of the time in a letter to William Short in 1825, saying, \"the latter fear the people, and wish to transfer all power to the higher classes of society. the former consider the people as the safest depository of power, in the ultimate, they cherish them therefore, and wish to leave in them all the powers to the exercise of which they are competent.\" which could be the source of the claimed quote. "
                    }
                ]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "What is sudden death syndrome?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Sudden death syndrome (SDS) is a loosely defined umbrella term for a series of cardiac syndromes that cause sudden cardiac arrest and possibly death.\n\nSome of these syndromes are the result of structural problems in the heart. Others may be the result of irregularities within the electrical channels. All may cause unexpected and abrupt cardiac arrest, even in people who are otherwise healthy. Some people die as a result of it.\n\nMost people don’t know they have the syndrome until a cardiac arrest occurs"
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "What causes Sudden Death Syndrome?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "It’s unclear what causes SDS.\n\nGene mutations have been linked to many of the syndromes that fall under the SDS umbrella, but not every person with SDS has the genes. It’s possible other genes are connected to SDS, but they haven’t been identified yet. And some SDS causes aren’t genetic.\n\nSome medications can cause the syndromes that may lead to sudden death. For example, long QT syndrome may result from using:\n\nantihistamines\ndecongestants\nantibiotics\ndiuretics\nantidepressants\nantipsychotics\nLikewise, some people with SDS may not show symptoms until they begin taking these certain medications. Then, the medication-induced SDS may appear."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Is there any evidence to show Coronavirus cases are linked to Sudden Death Syndrome",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "There is no evidence that the coronavirus causes sudden death syndrome.\n\nA Jan. 30 study of 99 coronavirus cases found that the virus \"can result in severe and even fatal respiratory diseases such as acute respiratory distress syndrome.\" Three-quarters of the patients in the study showed signs of double pneumonia, and the characteristics of those who died were consistent with a warning model that predicts who’s most likely to die from the disease."
                    }
                ]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "Is there any tax on school textbooks in India ?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Exim Code Item Description Policy Policy Conditions\n4901 PRINTED BOOKS, BROCHURES,\nLEAFLETS AND SIMILAR PRINTED\nMATTER, WHETHER OR NOT IN SINGLE\nSHEETS\n4901 10 In single sheets, whether or not folded:\n4901 10 10 Printed books Free\n4901 10 20 Pamphlets, booklets, brochures, leaflets and\nsimilar printed matter\nFree\nOther:\n4901 91 00 Dictionaries and encyclopaedias, and serial\ninstallments thereof\nFree\n4901 99 00 Other Free\n4902 NEWSPAPERS, JOURNALS AND\nPERIODICALS, WHETHER OR NOT\nILLUSTRATED OR CONTAINING\nADVERTISING MATERIAL\n4902 10 Appearing at least four times a week:\n4902 10 10 Newspapers Free\n4902 10 20 Journals and periodicals Free\n4902 90 Other:\n4902 90 10 Newspapers Free\n4902 90 20 Journals and periodicals Free\n4903 CHILDREN'S PICTURE, DRAWING OR\nCOLOURING BOOKS\n4903 00 Children's picture, drawing or colouring books:"
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Was GST (Goods and Services Tax) levied on school books in India ?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Book lovers and students will now have to pay more as books will become costlier by 10-20 per cent under the Goods and Services Tax regime. Though books continue to remain exempt under GST, but inputs such as printing, binding and royalties to authors now attract tax at 12 per cent. "
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Are books still exempt from  GST (Goods and Services Tax) in India?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Though books continue to remain exempt under GST, but inputs such as printing, binding and royalties to authors now attract tax at 12 per cent. "
                    }
                ]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "Did Donald Trump support the people in Hong Kong standing up for democracy?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "No answer could be found."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "How did Donald Trump intervene or support the people in Hong Kong who were standing up for democracy ?\n",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Indeed, Trump signed the two bills on Nov. 27. The first was S. 1838, the Hong Kong Human Rights and Democracy Act of 2019, which requires the U.S. to every year “assess whether political developments in Hong Kong justify changing Hong Kong’s unique treatment under U.S. law,” including not being subject to tariffs levied upon China. It also includes several human rights provisions. The second bill, S. 2710, prohibits the sale of “specified munitions” including tear gas, rubber bullets and handcuffs to the Hong Kong Police Force."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Did Trump sign Hong Kong bill despite China’s warnings ?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "President Donald Trump is expected to sign legislation passed by Congress supporting Hong Kong protesters, setting up a confrontation with China that could imperil a long-awaited trade deal between the world’s two largest economies.\n\nThe bill, approved unanimously by the Senate Tuesday, passed the House 417-1 on Wednesday and could go to Trump as soon as Thursday. A person familiar with the matter said Trump plans to sign the bill."
                    }
                ]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "What percent of the worlds sickle cell burden does Nigeria have?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "30% to 35% based on :\n\nNigeria is projected to increase from 30% (91,000 [CI: 77,900 (33%)–106,100 (27%)]) to 35% (140,800 [CI: 95,500 (39%)–200,600 (31%)])"
                    }
                ]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "What kind of hostility is this referring to?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "After Nevada’s Culinary Workers Union released a scorecard criticizing Sanders’ Medicare-for-All health care plan, union leadership faced a barrage of venom from supporters of the Vermont senator. Union spokeswoman Bethany Khan told the Nevada Independent they have been on the receiving end of dozens of angry phone calls, hundreds of emails, and thousands of tweets.“We will find you corrupt mother f***ers of that you can be sure and we will make sure you wallow in poverty and suffering,” one read."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "What did Bernie say about this?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Asked to respond, Bernie gave a perfunctory disavowal of those spreading hatred on his behalf and pointed out that members of his own campaign have been subject to online vitriol as well.\n\n“We have over 10.6 million people on Twitter, and 99.9 percent of them are decent human beings, are working people, are people who believe in justice, compassion, and love. And if there are a few people who make ugly remarks, who attack trade union leaders, I disown those people. They are not part of our movement.\n\n“But let me also say what I hope my friends up here will agree with is that if you look at the wild west of the internet, talk to some of the African-American women on my campaign. Talk to Senator Nina Turner. Talk to others and find the vicious, racist, sexist attacks that are coming their way, as well.”"
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Why does Sanders believe there is so much antagonism among his supporters?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "“All of us remember 2016,” he said. “What we remember is efforts by Russians and others to try to interfere in our election and divide us up. I'm not saying that's happening, but it would not shock me.”"
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Has Sanders publicly refuted any help from Russian president Vladmiri Putin?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Yes",
                        "bool_explanation": "Sanders told reporters the briefing took place about a month ago, and made clear to Russian president Vladimir Putin he didn’t want his support. “Here is the message to Russia: Stay out of American elections.”"
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Is there any evidence of Russian interference driving the recent disagreements?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "No",
                        "bool_explanation": "“We know that the Russian operation in 2016 and the follow-on operation that was taken down in October 2019 included accounts that posed as Sanders supporters, among other things,” Ben Nimmo, an expert on Russian disinformation campaigns, told The Dispatch. “But I've not seen any evidence that the recent Twitter traffic around internal splits in the Democratic Party was caused or driven by Russian operations.”"
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Have sanders supporters also been subjected to harassment too?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Yes",
                        "bool_explanation": "Members of the Sanders campaign—which did not respond to a request for comment—have certainly, as the senator said on Wednesday, been victim to online harassment as well. A quick Twitter search reveals that prominent Bernie surrogate and former Ohio state senator Nina Turner, for example, has been called “the stupidest person in politics” and much, much worse."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Are the supporters that are engaging in online harassment, verified as Sanders supporters living in the US?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Yes",
                        "bool_explanation": "For example, When a Twitter user disagreed with David Klion’s assertion that “you have to support Medicare For All or else you’re a bad person,” the well-known Bernie advocate simply replied, “go f*** yourself.”"
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "What are Bernie Sanders' thoughts on Russia?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "“Let me be clear: We must not live in denial while allowing Russia and other state actors to undermine our democracy or divide us,” the senator said in January. “Russia targets the divisions in our society; we will work to heal those divisions.”"
                    }
                ]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "What is Excise revenue?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Excise taxes are taxes levied on specific goods such\nas alcohol, tobacco, fuel and luxury goods, and also on\nactivities such as gambling. Hence they are sometimes\ncolloquially known as ‘sin taxes’"
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "What was Kenya's excise  revenue for 2003/04 compared to gdp?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Excise duty as % of GDP\n2003/2004 = 3.5%",
                        "bool_explanation": "Excise duty as % of GDP\n2003/2004 = 3.5%\n"
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "What was Kenya's excise  revenue for 2017/2018 compared to gdp?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Excise duty as % of GDP\n2017/2018 = 1.91%"
                    }
                ]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "Is the The Indian Government (BJP) quoted as saying that the Pradhan Mantri Matru Vandana Yojana programme (PMMVY) benefited more than 50 lakh women every year?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "yes in an infographic"
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "How many women are benefiting  every from the Pradhan Mantri Matru Vandana Yojana programme (PMMVY) ?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": " The maternity benefits under PMMVY are available to the eligible beneficiaries for first living child of family. About 51.70 lakh beneficiaries are covered annually under PMMVY. However, it has to be noted that this is the expected number of beneficiaries every year and the actual number of women who received the amount could be higher or lower than 50 lakh."
                    }
                ]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "What is the date of the claim?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "14th October 2020"
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Does New Zealand allow abortions at the time of the claim?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Around March 2020 New Zealand passed a landmark bill that treats abortion as a health issue rather than a crime,"
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "What does new Zealand's abortion law say about late abortions?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Under that law, abortions after 20-weeks gestation were only permitted if it was “necessary to save the life of the woman or girl or to prevent serious permanent injury to her physical or mental health”."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Can a fetus be left to die after birth under new Zealand's abortion law?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "New Zealand generally adheres to the born alive rule which is that newborn infants are distinguished from fetuses as fetuses are presumed dead until born.121\nThis would suggest “personhood” only crystalises at birth."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "What rights would a baby pre-viable baby have, who was born alive after a failed abortion?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "the same as any other previable neonate, 23+0 to 24+6 weeks gestation requires individualised care and counselling. Consideration for approach to care prior to 23+0 weeks should occur where possible because , if active intervention is the decision taken chosen from 23+0 weeks, preparation and therapy should commence at 22+5 weeks if already identified as at high risk of periviable delivery."
                    }
                ]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "Did Mukesh Ambani undergo surgery in New York for pancreatic cancer?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "A spokesperson of Reliance Industry Digital also confirmed to NewsMobile that the viral message is fake.\n\nHence, from the above information, it is clear that the viral message is fake."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Did Mukesh Ambani have pancreatic cancer?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "NewsMobile fact-checked the post and found the claim to be false.\n\nFirstly, we checked for media reports or any official announcement regarding the same but did not find any credible source.\n\nWhen we put the picture through Reverse Image Search, it led us to a post on Medium from September 2020 by Manushree Vijayvergiya who shared her experience of meeting Mukesh and Isha Ambani in a cafe in Liechtenstein. "
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Where does the claim originate?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "facebook posts."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Did Mukesh Ambani make any public appearances around the time of the claim  showing any ill health?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "a digital interview of Mukesh Ambani which was uploaded on Oct 19, 2020, where he seemed fine."
                    }
                ]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "What was Klobuchar referencing here?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Klobuchar was talking about the practical impact of climate change and severe weather events, from wildfires to tornadoes."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "What time frame was this 50% increase referencing?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "She gives no time frame, so the statement by itself is vague."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "What does insurance industry data show?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Insurance industry data shows that in constant dollars, between 2008 and 2017, the average cost of insuring a home rose 30%, not 50% as she said. (In nominal dollars, the increase was 45%, which is closer to her number.)"
                    }
                ]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "Can postal ballots lead to voting fraud?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "As with other forms of voting, documented cases of mail-ballot fraud are extremely rare.\n\nThe conservative Heritage Foundation, which has warned of the risks of mail voting, found 14 cases of attempted mail fraud out of roughly 15.5 million ballots cast in Oregon since that state started conducting elections by mail in 1998."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Does Mail-In Ballots Increase Risk of Voter Fraud?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "In practice, however, voter fraud is very rare, and the risk of widespread fraud is probably very minimal, even with all-mail elections. But nevertheless, as more voters cast their ballots through the mail, we should think about these issues and do what we can, within reason, to identify and mitigate fraud or coercion."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Was there a voter fraud in the 2020 U.S Presidential Election caused by mail-in ballots sent to a mans deceased parents in Mercer County in New Jersey?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "In prior years, New Jersey residents would have had to request a mail-in ballot, but in light of the pandemic, an executive order by Democratic governor Phil Murphy required election officials to automatically send ballots to all active registered voters.\n\nCovello, who has administered New Jersey’s mail-in voting since 2009, says these errors don’t threaten the integrity of the vote. “It’s worked out very well for us, we’ve seen very little instance of fraud.”\n\nCovello said that ballots received for deceased individuals should be returned to the sender with the word “deceased” written on the envelope. \n\nAccording to Kimberly Burnett, spokeswoman for New Jersey’s Middlesex County government, forged signatures on returned ballots “will be flagged by Board of Elections staff when researching signatures.” \n\nShe added in an email that “a flagged ballot will be referred to the county prosecutor for election fraud if our office determines a voter is deceased through a post-election audit.”\n\nA Florida Man was charged with voter fraud after requesting a ballot for this deceased wife, claiming he wanted to “test the system to see if it worked.” Supervisor of Elections staff conducted a routine check to process her application and noticed she had died in 2018."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Did a man receive ballots for the US election that were for his dead parents?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Yes they had been dead 8 years the man was from mercer county. The claim states \"potential\" fraud and not that a fraud occurred so supports claim."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Did anyone else receive ballots for people who had died?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Yes a man complained about receiving one for his mother-in-law who died five years ago (Claim states potential fraud not that fraud occurred so supports claim)"
                    },
                    {
                        "answer": "Another man said he received one for someone who had been dead for 17 years. The claim states potential fraud not that fraud occurred and this could lead to \"potential\" fraud."
                    }
                ]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "Where was this claim first published?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "News @ 7"
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Are News @ 7 a reliable source of factual news?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Its own site says... it is a satirical website that publish verified stories once in a while. These verified stories are tagged as such; VERIFIED NEWS."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Has the company in question released any report on the claim being true?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "A statement published on MTN Ghana’s twitter handle on January 18, confirms that data services across Ghana were soon fully restored."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Was there any data loss confirmed as is claimed?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Yes",
                        "bool_explanation": "Data on Qwikloan are stored securely and under no circumstance would an undersea fibre cut affect data storage for the service"
                    }
                ]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "Has/Is the Indian Government giving out  Rs.7,500 as relief fund to bereaved families?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "There is no record of this on the Indian Government website."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Where does the claim originate?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Viral message linking to: \n\nhttps://funds4-covid19.com/"
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "What is known about https://funds4-covid19.com/ ?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "The domain is not registered to the Indian Government."
                    }
                ]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "Which body administers Social Grants in South Africa?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "South African Social Security Agency (SASSA)"
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "What does the South African Social Security Agency  (SASSA) have to say about the number of social grants that have been provided?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "By the\nend of March 2018, there were 17 509 995 social grants in payment,\nincluding the Grant-in-Aid. "
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Does the SASSA give out  around 17.5 million  in social grants every month as is claimed?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Yes",
                        "bool_explanation": "The figure is a total for each month,"
                    }
                ]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "Can mouthwash protect from covid 19 virus?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "There is no evidence that using mouthwash will protect you from infection with the new coronavirus (2019-nCoV). "
                    }
                ]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "Has Instagram commented on the claim?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Yes they posted on twitter to say use a specific hashtag (#blackouttuesday) as tagging them with #blacklivesmatter would show up when people were trying to make informative #blacklivesmatter posts."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Did Posting on social media for Blackout Tuesday dilutes feeds and erases protesters’ posts ?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "If you edit your post to remove a hashtag, your post will no longer be shown on that hashtag page,” she said. “In some cases, it may take up to 10 minutes for the post to be removed once you edit it. If someone uses #blacklivesmatter and #blackouttuesday in their caption, the post will appear on both hashtag pages – we are not merging the pages.”"
                    }
                ]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "What event lead up to this claim?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "The police officer-involved death of George Floyd on May 25, 2020, in Minneapolis led to a call for nationwide law enforcement reform as demonstrators denounced police brutality during protests that swept across the country last summer.\n\nIn New York, Governor Andrew Cuomo issued Executive Order 203 in June to direct local police agencies statewide to review their forces and develop plans to improve them.\n\nThe directive led the city of Ithaca, New York, in collaboration with Tompkins County, to release a recommendations report on Monday that reimagines its public safety and law enforcement."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "What does the claim say the police will be replaced with?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "A twitter user posted, \"My state is a black hole of stupidity. Ithaca (NY) Mayor Calls for Abolishing Police Dept, Replacing With 'Community Solution Workers'"
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "What does the Mayor say he is doing?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "The Ithaca Police Department would be replaced with a \"Department of Community Solutions and Public Safety.\"\n\nThe plan would have armed public safety workers focus on interrupting and solving serious crimes and unarmed community solution workers who focus on de-escalation."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "What kind of calls would these Community Solution Workers handle?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "\"IPD currently spends one third of its time responding to calls for service that essentially never lead to arrests,\" Myrick wrote in the report. \"Those calls, as well as a majority of patrol activity can and should be handled by unarmed Community Solution Workers well trained in de-escalation and service delivery. This will allow our new Public Safety Workers to focus on preventing, interrupting and solving serious crime.\""
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "How would this department receive funding?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "The proposed civilian-led department would receive funding the same way the IPD receives funding through locally funded sales tax and property tax, according to Myrick."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Has this been approved?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "No",
                        "bool_explanation": "The Common Council has to approve this proposal, and city leaders expect a vote by the end of march.\n\n"
                    }
                ]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "In the Year leading up to the claim how much tax did amazon pay?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Amazon pays no federal income tax for 2018, despite soaring profits"
                    }
                ]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "When was this claim made?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "29/06/2020"
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Has the Ellen DeGeneres show been cancelled in 2020?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "No",
                        "bool_explanation": "DeGeneres’ production company reps said, “Telepictures can confirm it’s untrue.”"
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Has the Ellen DeGeneres Show been extended beyond 2020?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Yes",
                        "bool_explanation": "\"THE ELLEN DEGENERES SHOW\" WILL EXTEND ITS RUN THROUGH 2022\n\nMay 22, 2019\nBurbank, CA – Ellen DeGeneres will continue her number-one and award-winning talk show for the next three seasons she announced today to thunderous applause from the studio audience on Stage 1 at Warner Bros. Studios on the episode of \"The Ellen DeGeneres Show\" airing on Wednesday, May 22nd."
                    }
                ]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "Was there news coverage of President Trump signing an EO yesterday protecting pre-existing conditions?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Yes",
                        "bool_explanation": "The LA Times covered President Trump's travel to North Carolina on Thursday to announce his commitment to protecting Americans with pre-existing medical conditions and to issue another round of executive orders related to healthcare."
                    },
                    {
                        "answer": "Yes",
                        "bool_explanation_second": "Healthline covered President Trump's signing of the executive order that claims to help protect Americans with preexisting conditions like cancer, asthma, or diabetes."
                    },
                    {
                        "answer": "Yes",
                        "bool_explanation_third": "NBC News covered President Donald Trump's announcement of two new health care executive orders Thursday on protecting pre-existing conditions and preventing surprise billing as the president sought to shore up his support on an issue that remains top of mind to voters amid the ongoing coronavirus pandemic."
                    }
                ]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "Has Israel developed a super-quick saliva test for COVID-19?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Yes",
                        "bool_explanation": "The Israeli Sheba Medical Center created a 1-second saliva test for COVID-19. "
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "How accurate is the super-quick saliva test?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "1-second Covid spit test shown 95% accurate so far"
                    }
                ]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "What is criminal justice reform?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Criminal justice reform addresses structural issues in criminal justice systems such as racial profiling, police brutality, overcriminalization, mass incarceration, and recidivism. Reforms can take place at any point where the criminal justice system intervenes in citizens’ lives, including lawmaking, policing, sentencing and incarceration. Criminal justice reform can also address the collateral consequences of conviction, including disenfranchisement or lack of access to housing or employment, that may restrict the rights of individuals with criminal records."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Who enacted the criminal justice reform?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Congress passed two pieces of legislation that the American Bar Association supported and lobbied for — the reauthorization of the Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Act (JJDPA) and the First Step Act. President Donald Trump signed both into law Friday, Dec. 21, marking the most significant legislative progress towards criminal justice system reform in a generation. Both bills passed with overwhelming bipartisan support."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Did the Obama administration work towards criminal justice reform?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "President Obama signed a bill Tuesday reducing the disparity in penalties for the use of crack and powder cocaine, according to the White House.\n\nThe enactment of the law seals a hard-fought victory for civil rights activists who have argued for years that the differing punishments unfairly target African-Americans.\n\nThe Fair Sentencing Act repeals a five-year mandatory sentence for first time offenders, and for repeat offenders with less than 28 grams of crack cocaine. The old law set the mandatory sentence for conviction at five grams.\n\nAfrican-Americans have been far more likely than whites and Hispanics to be convicted for -- and receive the harsher penalties associated with -- possession of crack cocaine, according to government statistics. White and Hispanic defendants are more frequently charged with possession of powder cocaine.\n\nThe now-defunct measure had been in place for 25 years. The House passed the new law through a bipartisan voice vote last week, following approval by the Senate in March."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Did the bipartisan Fair Sentencing Act see a reduction in the federal prison population?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Yes",
                        "bool_explanation": "Chief Judge Patti B. Saris, Chair of the Commission, said: “We found that the Fair Sentencing Act\nreduced the disparity between crack and powder cocaine sentences, substantially reduced the\nfederal prison population, and resulted in fewer federal prosecutions for crack cocaine. All this\noccurred while crack cocaine use continued to decline.”\n\nTo assess the impact of the FSA, the Commission analyzed external data sources and undertook\nstatistical analyses of its own federal sentencing data spanning before and after the enactment of\nthe FSA. Among other things, the study shows that:\n• Many fewer crack cocaine offenders have been prosecuted annually since the FSA,\nalthough the number is still substantial;\n• Crack cocaine offenders prosecuted after the FSA are, on average, about as serious as\nthose prosecuted before the FSA;\n• Rates of crack cocaine offenders cooperating with law enforcement have not changed\ndespite the reduction in penalties; and,\n• Average crack cocaine sentences are lower, and are now closer to average powder cocaine\nsentences.\nThe Fair Sentencing Act of 2010 (FSA), Pub. L. No. 111-220, signed by the President on August\n3, 2010, reduced the statutory penalties for crack cocaine trafficking and eliminated the mandatory\nminimum sentence for simple possession of crack cocaine."
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "What is the First Step Act?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "The FIRST STEP Act shortens mandatory minimum sentences for nonviolent drug offenses. It also eases a federal “three strikes” rule — which currently imposes a life sentence for three or more convictions — and issues a 25-year sentence instead. Most consequentially, it expands the “drug safety-valve,” which would give judges more discretion to deviate from mandatory minimums when sentencing for nonviolent drug offenses.\n\nIn an overdue change, the bill also makes the Fair Sentencing Act retroactive. Passed in 2010, the Fair Sentencing Act has helped reduce the sentencing disparity between crack and powder cocaine offenses — a disparity that has hurt racial minorities. The FIRST STEP Act will now apply the Fair Sentencing Act to 3,000 people who were convicted of crack offenses before the law went into effect."
                    }
                ]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "Has Israel developed a super-quick saliva test for COVID-19?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Yes",
                        "bool_explanation": "The Israeli Sheba Medical Center created a 1-second saliva test for COVID-19. "
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "How accurate is the super-quick saliva test?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "1-second Covid spit test shown 95% accurate so far"
                    }
                ]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "Is US Mayor Bill De Blasio quoted as saying federal prosecutors told the city of New York that they could not proceed with the case of murder of Eric Garner because the Justice Department was pursuing their prosecution.?",
                "answers": [
                    {
                        "answer": "Yes",
                        "bool_explanation": "\"You know why? Because for the first time, we are not waiting on the federal Justice Department, which told the city of New York that we could not proceed because the Justice Department was pursuing their prosecution. ...\""
                    }
                ]
            }
        ]
    }
]